<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Search><pages Count="16"><page Index="1"><![CDATA[VDG_EN_cover9_Layout 1  16-Mar-16  2:39 PM  Page 1









                                                                                                                                                    Mina Ricci

                                                                         Via della Grammatica

                                                                                             for English speakers
                                                                                                                                     Mina Ricci
                                                                         Theory, exercises, tests and authentic material for foreigners








                                                                                                                                                                      Via della Grammatica



                                                                                                                                                                                                   for English speakers


                                                                                                                                                                     Theory, exercises, tests and authentic material for foreigners
                     Via della Grammatica for English speakers is a practical and straightforward introduction to all the
                     essential grammar points of Italian in a single volume. It is designed for beginner to intermediate level
                     students (A1-B2 Common European Framework of Reference for Languages).


                     Via della Grammatica for English speakers comprises:                                                             for English speakers

                     • 40 units, each one dealing with one or more areas of grammar using clear and simple language
                     • A revision test every 5 units enabling students to check their progress independently
                     • Grammar points provided in clear and concise tables, which explain standard and practical use of
                        grammar rules
                     • A wide range of exercises, tests, stimulating and entertaining activities, enabling students to practise
                        the grammar rules they have learned
                     • Terminology introduced gradually that reflects current everyday Italian; in some cases new semantic
                        groups are presented with images to facilitate learning
                     • Authentic materials on a range of cultural, literary and everyday themes providing students with the
                        opportunity to enrich and widen their knowledge of Italian society, history and civilisation
                     • A contemporary and attractive format with many photographs                                                     Via della Grammatica Via della Grammatica
                     • Keys to the exercises making this grammar book very useful for independent learners
                     • A glossary is available on www.edilingua.it

                     Via della Grammatica for English speakers is completed by i-d-e-e, a platform that includes the exercises
                     in interactive form and extra material and digital tools for both students and teachers.

                     Via della Grammatica for English speakers is an essential tool for teachers. It can be used as a text
                     book with an Italian language course, or as a means of study and evaluation for those who wish to learn
                     and practise the language on their own.

                     You can download for free the multilingual Glossary from our website.
                                                                    La Terra
                                                                  ha bisogno di aiuto...
                                                                   del tuo aiuto!
                                                                                                ISBN 978-960-693-050-8
                                                                      Edilingua
                                                                        supports

                                                                 Edili ng ua p er l’am biente
                                                                  www.edilingua.it

                 Via della Grammatica
                for English speakers
                                This volume without the side coupon is to be considered “sample copy” not for sale.]]></page><page Index="2"><![CDATA[VDG_prime e indice_EN167_1. I nomi in o a e  16-Mar-16  12:00 PM  Page 2









                     Mina Ricci obtained a first degree in Foreign Languages and Literatures from the University of
                     Mo dern Languages in Milan (IULM), followed by a Masters in Translation at the University of West -
                     min ster in London. She has taught Italian in various companies and institutions, such as the Italian
                     Cul tural Institute in Dublin and the Applied Languages Centre at University College Dublin. She
                     has also taught Italian language and culture for several years in the Department of Italian in the
                     School of Languages and Literatures at University College Dublin.






                                                                                                    To my dear father
                                                                                                    Paolo Maria Ricci








                     © Copyright edizioni Edilingua
                     Sede legale                                                                          Edilingua
                                                                                                            supports
                     Via Alberico II, 4  00193 Roma
                     Tel. +39 06 96727307
                                                                                                    Thanks to the sale of our
                     Fax +39 06 94443138                                                            books, Edilingua sponsors
                     info@edilingua.it o                                                            children who live in Asia,
                                                                                                   Africa and South America.
                     www.edilingua.it                                                                  Because together we
                                                                                                          can do so much!
                                                                                                       For more information
                                                                                                          see our website.
                     Deposito e Centro di distribuzione                                                              .
                     Via Moroianni, 65  12133 Atene
                     Tel. +30 210 5733900
                     Fax +30 210 5758903



                     First edition: June 2021
                     Editors: Antonio Bidetti, Marco Dominici, Laura Piccolo
                     Layout and graphics: Edilingua, Edigraf
                     Illustrations: Davide Ceccon
                     Translation: Stella Cragie
                     ISBN: 979-12-5980-019-0













                     We welcome any suggestions and comments on this book (please send to redazione@edilingua.it).

                     All worldwide rights reserved. No part of this publication may be reproduced or transmitted in any form or by any
                     means, electronic or mechanical, including microfilm, photocopy, recording or any other information storage and
                     retrieval system.

                     Edilingua is happy to correspond with any unascertained holders of copyright and to correct any omissions or errors in
                     the bibliographic references.]]></page><page Index="3"><![CDATA[VDG_prime e indice_EN:1. I nomi in o a e  15/4/2011  5:10 ìì  Page 3









                                                                PREFACE




                     Via della Grammatica is suitable for young adults and adults at beginner-intermediate level (A1-
                     B2 Common European Framework of Reference for Languages) and for LS/L2 Italian language
                     courses.
                     This text is a practical and straightforward grammar book consisting of 40 Units, each of which
                     deals with one or more areas of grammar. In each Unit grammar is presented using clear and con-
                     cise tables, which provide standard and practical use of the rules, rather than theoretical analysis.
                     The grammar points are accompanied by a wide range of stimulating and enjoyable activities,
                     enabling students to learn empirically and to practise using Italian grammar rules. Information
                     about aspects of everyday life, culture and, in some cases, literature – introduced through many
                     exercises and activities – encourages students to enrich and widen their knowledge of Italian soci-
                     ety, history and civilisation. This information is often in the form of authentic materials, including
                     articles from the press, literature, publicity and songs.

                     Lexis is introduced gradually, and reflects the use of current everyday language. To make the
                     activities more interesting, new semantic groups are sometimes presented with an image to aid
                     learning.

                     At the end of every 5 Units, a set of exercises tests the grammar taught in those Units. The 8 tests
                     are complete with self-assessment tools, which provide plenty of opportunity for independent
                     learning.

                     Via della Grammatica can be used as a teaching tool for learning and checking grammar in a vari-
                     ety of Italian courses. Assisted by the keys to the tests, the book is ideal for self-study. For this
                     reason, it can be used independently or combined with a course book for teaching Italian to for-
                     eigners.

                                                                                                          The Author]]></page><page Index="4"><![CDATA[VDG_prime e indice_EN:1. I nomi in o a e  15/4/2011  5:11 ìì  Page 4



















                     Unit 1            I nomi / Nouns                                                       pag. 7

                     Unit 2            Nomi particolari / Unusual nouns (invariable and with irregular plural forms)  pag. 11

                     Unit 3            Gli articoli determinativi / Definite articles                       pag. 16

                     Unit 4            Gli articoli indeterminativi / Indefinite article                    pag. 20

                     Unit 5            I verbi essere, avere, esserci / Essere, avere, esserci (present indicative)  pag. 23

                                       Test 1 (units 1-5)                                                   pag. 27

                     Unit 6            Gli aggettivi qualificativi / Qualifying adjectives                  pag. 31

                     Unit 7            Il presente indicativo dei verbi regolari / Present indicative of regular verbs  pag. 36

                     Unit 8            Il presente indicativo dei verbi irregolari, dei verbi modali e del verbo sapere /
                                       Present indicative of irregular verbs, modals and the verb sapere    pag. 41


                     Unit 9            I pronomi personali soggetto / Subject pronouns and polite form      pag. 47

                     Unit 10           I dimostrativi / Demonstratives                                      pag. 51

                                       Test 2 (units 6-10)                                                  pag. 56

                     Unit 11           I possessivi / Possessives                                           pag. 61

                     Unit 12           I pronomi diretti / Direct object pronouns                           pag. 65

                     Unit 13           I verbi riflessivi (presente indicativo) / Reflexive verbs (present indicative)  pag. 69

                     Unit 14           Stare (per) + ... / The forms stare + gerund and stare + infinitive  pag. 73

                     Unit 15           Le preposizioni / Prepositions and expressions of place and time     pag. 77

                                       Test 3 (units 11-15)                                                 pag. 90


                     Unit 16           La forma impersonale / Impersonal verbs                              pag. 96

                     Unit 17           Il passato prossimo / Present perfect (with the pronouns and modal verbs)  pag. 100

                     Unit 18           I pronomi indiretti / Indirect object pronouns                       pag. 113

                     Unit 19           L’imperfetto indicativo / Imperfect indicative (imperfect and present perfect)  pag. 116

                     Unit 20           I pronomi relativi / Relative pronouns                               pag. 124

                                       Test 4 (units 16-20)                                                 pag. 129

                    4                                                                                   edizioni Edilingua]]></page><page Index="5"><![CDATA[VDG_prime e indice_EN:1. I nomi in o a e  15/4/2011  5:11 ìì  Page 5



















                     Unit 21           Il futuro (semplice e anteriore) / Future (simple and perfect)       pag. 134
                     Unit 22           I pronomi combinati / Combined pronouns                              pag. 143

                     Unit 23           Ci e ne / Ci and ne (combined pronouns with ci and ne, combined pronoun ce ne)  pag. 149

                     Unit 24           Il condizionale (presente e passato) / Conditional (present and past)  pag. 164

                     Unit 25           I pronomi diretti e indiretti forti / Direct and indirect disjunctive pronouns  pag. 173

                                       Test 5 (units 21-25)                                                 pag. 176

                     Unit 26           I gradi dell’aggettivo / Degrees of adjectives: positive, comparative,
                                       superlative (irregular comparatives and superlatives)                pag. 181

                     Unit 27           L’imperativo diretto / Direct imperative (direct imperative and pronouns)  pag. 188

                     Unit 28           Il congiuntivo / Subjunctive (present, perfect, imperfect, pluperfect)     pag. 195

                     Unit 29           L’imperativo indiretto / Indirect imperative                         pag. 206

                     Unit 30           Gli indefiniti / Indefinite forms (adjectives, pronouns, adverbs)    pag. 211

                                       Test 6 (units 26-30)                                                 pag. 216

                     Unit 31           Il passato remoto / Past definite                                    pag. 221

                     Unit 32           Il trapassato prossimo / Pluperfect                                  pag. 227

                     Unit 33           Il trapassato remoto / Past anterior                                 pag. 230
                     Unit 34           La concordanza all’indicativo / Sequence of tense in the indicative  pag. 233

                     Unit 35           La concordanza al congiuntivo / Sequence of tense in the subjunctive  pag. 236

                                       Test 7 (units 31-35)                                                 pag. 239

                     Unit 36           Gli interrogativi / Interrogative forms (adverbs, pronouns, adjectives)   pag. 245

                     Unit 37           Il periodo ipotetico / Conditional sentences                         pag. 249

                     Unit 38           I modi indefiniti / Non-conjugated verb forms
                                       (present and past infinitive, present and past gerund, present and past participle)  pag. 255

                     Unit 39           La forma passiva / The Passive                                       pag. 268
                     Unit 40           Il discorso indiretto / Indirect speech                              pag. 278

                                       Test 8 (units 36-40)                                                 pag. 288
                                                                                                                           Indice
                                       Chiavi / Key to exercises                                            pag. 295



                                                                                              Via della Grammatica   5]]></page><page Index="6"><![CDATA[VDG_prime e indice_EN:1. I nomi in o a e  15/4/2011  5:11 ìì  Page 6]]></page><page Index="7"><![CDATA[1. I nomi in -o -a -e_EN:1. I nomi in o a e  15/4/2011  5:12 ìì  Page 7



















                     Nouns ending in -o and -a


                                       SINGULAR                                          PLURAL
                            masculine                feminine               masculine                feminine
                                o                       a                        i                      e


                                                                               ragazzo           ragazzi
                            Nouns ending in -o are usually masculine          quaderno          quaderni
                            The plural of nouns ending in -o is -i.
                                                                               bambino           bambini

                                                                               ragazza           ragazze
                            Nouns ending in -a are usually feminine             penna             penne
                            The plural of nouns ending in -a is -e.
                                                                                chiesa           chiese



                     Nouns ending in -e

                                       SINGULAR                                          PLURAL

                            masculine                feminine               masculine                feminine
                                e                       e                        i                       i


                            Nouns ending in -e are may be masculine
                                                                        (m)    giornale          giornali
                            or feminine.
                                                                        (f)     chiave            chiavi
                            The plural of nouns ending in -e is -i.

                                                                                attore            attori
                            Nouns ending in -tore, -ale, -ile are usually       canale            canali
                            masculine.
                                                                                fucile            fucili

                                                                                attrice           attrici
                            Nouns ending in -trice are usually feminine.        lezione          lezioni
                            Nouns ending in -zione are always feminine.
                                                                               stazione          stazioni





                     EXERCISES

               1.1   Find these 9 nouns in the grid then say whether they are masculine or feminine, as in the example.
                                                                                                                           01. I nomi
                                               penna    canale    tavolo    libro    porta
                                                finestra    attore    lezione     mamma



                                                                                              Via della Grammatica   7]]></page><page Index="8"><![CDATA[1. I nomi in -o -a -e_EN:1. I nomi in o a e  7/4/2011  4:38 ìì  Page 8






                     01. I nomi




                       A     L    E    Z     I   O     N    E    C           masculine               feminine

                       T    A     V    O    L    O     A    M    A                                    lezione

                       T    C     D    F    L     T    V    A    N

                       O     L    I    B    R    O     R    M    A

                       R    O     R    T    Y     E    P    M    L

                       E    P    M     R    A    C     G    A    E

                       G     L    E    O    S    P     B    U    U

                       F     I    N    E    S     T    R    A    G

                       S    A     C    T    P    O     R    T    A

                       P     E    N    N    A    A     V    O    L




               1.2   Put the nouns in the correct circle, as in the example. If in doubt, use the dictionary.

                             piazza           scultore         albero           padre           televisione
                              chiave           cane             fiore           treno            attrice
                              strada          giornale         lezione         stazione      appartamento






                                      masculine                                      feminine
                                                                             piazza



















               1.3   Put -o, -a or -e at the end of each noun and say if it is masculine (m) or feminine (f), as in the
                     example in blue.

                                      lettera (f)               regal_                     cappell_
                                      scultric_                 music_                     stanz_
                                      ciel_                     luc_                       pittor_
                                      mar_                      nazion_                    cas_
                    8                                                                                   edizioni Edilingua]]></page><page Index="9"><![CDATA[1. I nomi in -o -a -e_EN:1. I nomi in o a e  7/4/2011  4:38 ìì  Page 9











               1.4   Put these nouns in the singular or plural, as in the example in blue.


                                libro            libri                        quaderno         ........................
                                zaino            ........................     porta            ........................
                                cortile          ........................     ........................  chiese
                                ........................  dottori             lavagna          ........................
                                cane             ........................     ........................  lezioni
                                ........................  tavoli              ........................  cieli
                                ragazzo          ........................     gatto            ........................



               1.5   Complete the table with the nouns then put the numbers corresponding to the nouns in the picture.

                                                             La classe di Anna
                     Questa è la classe di An na. C’è una lavagna(1). Ci sono banchi(2) e se die(3). Ci sono due finestre(4) con le
                     tende(5), una por ta(6) e una cartina(7) geografica sulla pa rete. C’è anche un cestino(8).















                                               1

























                                          Masculine                                   Feminine
                                singular               plural               singular               plural
                                                                                                                           01. I nomi
                             ........................  ........................  lavagna       ........................
                                                                         ........................  ........................
                                                                         ........................  ........................



                                                                                              Via della Grammatica   9]]></page><page Index="10"><![CDATA[1. I nomi in -o -a -e_EN:1. I nomi in o a e  7/4/2011  4:39 ìì  Page 10






                     01. I nomi



               1.6   Look at the pictures and complete the crossword, as in the example.





                                                                          2


                                                                                                      3







                                   1
                                               2        3
                                            1


                                                                                                               4
                                                     4  L   E   T   T   E R E

                               10
                                                                6       7       8
                                                     5

                                                                             9



                                                                                                               5

                                               10










                                9



                                                                                                               6









                                                                                   7




                                  8




                   10                                                                                   edizioni Edilingua]]></page><page Index="11"><![CDATA[2. I nomi plurale irregolare_EN:2. I nomi plurale irregolare  15/4/2011  5:13 ìì  Page 11



















                     Nouns with unusual plurals


                     Noun group ending in -a

                           Some nouns ending in -a are masculine and  poeta       (m)           poeti
                           form the plural with -i                    problema    (m)           problemi
                                                                      programma (m)             programmi


                                                                         Careful!
                                                                      cinema      (m)           cinema

                           Nouns ending in -ista are can be masculine  farmacista (m)           farmacisti
                           or feminine.  The singular is always  -ista  farmacista (f)          farmaciste
                           while the plural form changes.             giornalista (m)           giornalisti
                                                                      giornalista (f)           giornaliste

                           The plural of nouns ending in -cia and -gia  camicia   (f)           camicie
                           is -cie and -gie if the group is preceded by a  valigia  (f)         valigie
                           vowel.                                     doccia      (f)           docce
                           The plural of nouns ending in -cia and -gia  arancia   (f)           arance
                           is -ce and -ge if the group is preceded by a  pioggia  (f)           piogge
                           consonant.                                 spiaggia    (f)           spiagge


                                                                         Careful!
                           When the -i in -cia and -gia is stressed the  farmacia  (f)          farmacie
                           plural is always -cie and -gie             bugia       (f)           bugie
                                                                      allergia    (f)           allergie

                           The plural of masculine nouns ending in -ca  duca      (m)           duchi
                           and -ga is -chi and -ghi.                  collega     (m)           colleghi
                           The plural of feminine nouns ending in -ca  amica      (f)           amiche
                           and -ga is -che and -ghe.                  collega     (f)           colleghe


                     Noun group ending in -o


                           The plural of nouns of two syllables ending  fuoco    (m)            fuochi
                                                                                                                           02. Nomi particolari
                           in -co and -go is -chi and -ghi.           luogo      (m)            luoghi
                                                                      cuoco      (m)            cuochi

                                                                         Careful!

                           The plural of nouns of more than two sylla-  tedesco  (m)            tedeschi
                           bles ending in -co and -go is -chi and -ghi if  albergo  (m)         alberghi
                           -co and -go are preceded by a consonant.



                                                                                              Via della Grammatica  11]]></page><page Index="12"><![CDATA[2. I nomi plurale irregolare_EN:2. I nomi plurale irregolare  15/4/2011  5:13 ìì  Page 12






                      02. Nomi particolari





                            But the plural of nouns of more than two   nemico     (m)           nemici
                            syllables ending in -co and -go is -ci and -gi  asparago  (m)       asparagi
                            if -co and -go are preceded by a vowel.    medico     (m)           medici

                            Important!                                    Careful!

                            As you can see, there are many exceptions  carico     (m)           carichi
                            to this rule. If in doubt, look up the noun in  obbligo  (m)        obblighi
                            your dictionary.


                            The plural of nouns ending in -logo is -logi if  psicologo  (m)     psicologi
                            they refer to people.                      radiologo  (m)           radiologi


                            The plural of other nouns ending in -logo is  catalogo  (m)         cataloghi
                            -loghi if they refer to things.            dialogo    (m)           dialoghi


                            The plural of masculine nouns ending in -io  figlio   (m)           figli
                            is -i, but when the -i is stressed the plural is  occhio  (m)       occhi
                            -ii.                                       bacio      (m)           baci
                                                                       zio        (m)           zii



                     Invariable nouns



                           Nouns ending in -à, -è and -ù have the sa -  città         (f)       città
                           me singular and plural form.               università      (f)       università
                                                                      caffè           (m)       caffè
                                                                      tè              (m)       tè
                                                                      gioventù        (f)       gioventù
                                                                      tribù           (f)       tribù
                                                                      menù            (m)       menù
                                                                      ragù            (m)       ragù

                           Some nouns ending in -o have the same sin-  video          (m)       video
                           gular and plural form. These are often abbre-  stereo      (m)       stereo
                           viations.                                  moto(cicletta)  (f)       moto
                                                                      auto(mobile)    (f)       auto
                                                                      radio(fonia)    (f)       radio
                                                                      foto(grafia)    (f)       foto
                                                                      frigo(rifero)   (m)       frigo

                           Many nouns ending in -ie are feminine and  serie           (f)       serie
                           have the same singular and plural form.    specie          (f)       specie

                                                                          Careful!


                                                                      moglie          (f)       mogli


                   12                                                                                   edizioni Edilingua]]></page><page Index="13"><![CDATA[2. I nomi plurale irregolare_EN:2. I nomi plurale irregolare  15/4/2011  5:14 ìì  Page 13












                           Masculine and feminine nouns of foreign ori-      autobus  (m)      autobus
                           gin are the same in the singular and plural.  film     (m)          film
                                                                        file      (m)          file
                                                                        brioche   (f)          brioche
                                                                        toilette  (f)          toilette
                                                                        e-mail    (f)          e-mail

                           Nouns ending in -i are often feminine and ha -  metropoli (f)       metropoli
                           ve the same singular and plural form.        tesi      (f)          tesi
                                                                        crisi     (f)          crisi



                     Nouns with irregular plural forms


                           Some nouns are masculine singular (-o) and  uovo        (m)          uova      (f)
                           feminine plural (-a).                      lenzuolo     (m)          lenzuola  (f)
                           This group includes nouns indicating parts  dito        (m)          dita      (f)
                           of the body.                               braccio      (m)          braccia   (f)
                                                                      ginocchio    (m)          ginocchia (f)



                                                                          Careful!

                                                                      mano         (f)          mani      (f)

                           Some unusual nouns have a plural that is   uomo         (m)          uomini
                           quite different to the singular.           dio          (m)          dei
                                                                      bue          (m)          buoi



                                                                                Il Duomo, Milano

                     EXERCISES

               2.1   Tick the correct box.

                                               SINGULAR          PLURAL
                     11. armadio
                     12. colleghe
                     13. ginocchio

                     14. pacco
                     15. operai
                     16. alberghi
                     17. programma
                     18. giornaliste                                                                                       02. Nomi particolari
                     19. pioggia
                     10. psicologi




                                                                                              Via della Grammatica  13]]></page><page Index="14"><![CDATA[2. I nomi plurale irregolare_EN127_2. I nomi plurale irregolare  12-Jun-15  11:29 AM  Page 14






                      02. Nomi particolari



               2.2   Choose the correct plural.

                     1. problema    a. n problemi                 6. città       a. n città
                                    b. n probleme                                b. n cittè
                                    c. n problemo                                c. n cittì

                     2. negozio     a. n negozie                  7. spiaggia    a. n spiaggie
                                    b. n negozia                                 b. n spiaggio
                                    c. n negozi                                  c. n spiagge

                     3. luogo       a. n luoghe                   8. auto        a. n auto
                                    b. n luoghi                                  b. n auti
                                    c. n luoghu                                  c. n aute

                     4. mano        a. n mane                     9. cuoco       a. n cuoche
                                    b. n mani                                    b. n cuochi
                                    c. n manu                                    c. n cuochu

                     5. camping     a. n camping                 10. barca       a. n barce
                                    b. n campings                                b. n barchi
                                    c. n campingi                                c. n barche



               2.3   Make words, as in the example.


                                che        ce        gne        che        le        chi        gie
                                che        ce         gne         che        le        chi        gie
                                1. Cilie        .............  3. Albicoc     .............  5. Me       ...........












                   Pes    che  .............    2. Fi        .............  4. Pru         .............  6. Aran       ..........




               2.4   Put the nouns in the plural.

                     Gianni vive da poco in una nuova zona di Roma. È molto con-
                     tento perché è una zona  bella e tranquilla con molto verde. Ci
                     sono, infatti, due (1.   ).............................. Poi ci so no (2.
                          )............................., (3.   )............................., (4.
                       )............................. e due (5.   )..............................  Ci
                     so no anche due (6.        )............................. vicino a casa
                     sua, che possono sempre essere utili.


                   14                                                                                   edizioni Edilingua]]></page><page Index="15"><![CDATA[]]></page><page Index="16"><![CDATA[VDG_EN_cover9_Layout 1  16-Mar-16  2:39 PM  Page 1









                                                                                                                                                    Mina Ricci

                                                                         Via della Grammatica

                                                                                             for English speakers
                                                                                                                                     Mina Ricci
                                                                         Theory, exercises, tests and authentic material for foreigners








                                                                                                                                                                      Via della Grammatica



                                                                                                                                                                                                   for English speakers


                                                                                                                                                                     Theory, exercises, tests and authentic material for foreigners
                     Via della Grammatica for English speakers is a practical and straightforward introduction to all the
                     essential grammar points of Italian in a single volume. It is designed for beginner to intermediate level
                     students (A1-B2 Common European Framework of Reference for Languages).


                     Via della Grammatica for English speakers comprises:                                                             for English speakers

                     • 40 units, each one dealing with one or more areas of grammar using clear and simple language
                     • A revision test every 5 units enabling students to check their progress independently
                     • Grammar points provided in clear and concise tables, which explain standard and practical use of
                        grammar rules
                     • A wide range of exercises, tests, stimulating and entertaining activities, enabling students to practise
                        the grammar rules they have learned
                     • Terminology introduced gradually that reflects current everyday Italian; in some cases new semantic
                        groups are presented with images to facilitate learning
                     • Authentic materials on a range of cultural, literary and everyday themes providing students with the
                        opportunity to enrich and widen their knowledge of Italian society, history and civilisation
                     • A contemporary and attractive format with many photographs                                                     Via della Grammatica Via della Grammatica
                     • Keys to the exercises making this grammar book very useful for independent learners
                     • A glossary is available on www.edilingua.it

                     Via della Grammatica for English speakers is completed by i-d-e-e, a platform that includes the exercises
                     in interactive form and extra material and digital tools for both students and teachers.

                     Via della Grammatica for English speakers is an essential tool for teachers. It can be used as a text
                     book with an Italian language course, or as a means of study and evaluation for those who wish to learn
                     and practise the language on their own.

                     You can download for free the multilingual Glossary from our website.
                                                                    La Terra
                                                                  ha bisogno di aiuto...
                                                                   del tuo aiuto!
                                                                      Edilingua
                                                                        supports

                                                                 Edili ng ua p er l’am biente
                                                                  www.edilingua.it]]></page></pages></Search>
